cosmeticscop.com 2019-03-04

# CosmeticsCop.com WebSite Privacy Policy - The Cosmetics Cop

Last Revised: January 31, 2019

#### INTRODUCTION

This Privacy Policy has been developed in order to inform you of practices with respect to the collection, use, disclosure and protection of your Information, as defined below. By using this Site you agree to the terms of the Privacy Policy.

This privacy policy (“policy”) describes the types of Information that CosmeticsCop.com may collect from you or that you may provide when you visit www.CosmeticsCop.com (the “Site”) and how that Information is collected, used, maintained, protected, and disclosed.

This policy applies to Information that may be collected via the Site and via email, text, or other electronic messages between you and CosmeticsCop.com.

This policy does not apply to Information collected when you leave this Site and continue to another site. 

By accessing or using the Site, you agree to this policy. If you do not agree with this policy, then you should not access or use the Site. 

This policy may change from time to time. Your continued use of the Site after changes are made constitutes your acceptance of those changes, and applies to your use of the Site after the effective date of the changes.  Any Information collected from you by the Site prior to the changes is subject to the Privacy Policy for the Site in effect at the time you submitted the Information.

#### INTERNATIONAL USERS

If you are outside the United States or Canada, and you decide to access or use the Site and share your personal information with us, you are consenting to the transfer of your personal information from your current location to the offices and servers of this Site in the United States, and the processing and storage of it by the Site in the United States. Your personal information will be processed in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

#### INFORMATION THAT MAY BE COLLECTED ABOUT YOU ﻿

The following Personal Information and Non-Personal Information from you may be collected when you use the Site:

“Personal Information” is information that identifies you personally, which may include your name, e-mail address, or any other identifier by which you may be contacted online or offline.

“Non-Personal Information” is information that does not identify you personally, such as your browser type, your internet connection, your IP address, the URL of the previous web site you visited, the equipment you use to access the Site, and details about how you use the Site.

This policy refers to Personal Information and Non-Personal Information collectively as “Information.”

#### HOW YOUR INFORMATION IS COLLECTED﻿

We may collect Information about you (1) when you provide it to us, and (2) automatically throughout the Site.

**Information You Provide to Us**  
You may provide your Information when you:

  * Visit the Site
  * Contact anyone at CosmeticsCop.com
  * Submit a question or product review
  * Comment in a post to an article

#### INFORMATION MAY BE COLLECTED AUTOMATICALLY

Information may be collected automatically when you access the Site by the utilization of automatic data collection technologies to spontaneously collect certain Information about you, including:

Details of your visits to the Site, including traffic data, location data (based on IP address), logs, and other communication data and the resources that you access and use on the Site; or Information about your computer and internet connection, including your IP address, operating system, and browser type. CosmeticsCop.com or its service providers may use some of the following technologies to automatically collect Information about your activities on our Site. 

**Cookies**  
Cookies are small files placed on the hard drive of your computer. You may refuse to accept browser cookies by activating the appropriate setting on your browser. However, if you refuse cookies you may be unable to access certain parts of our Site. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you direct your browser to our Site. Depending on which browser and browser version and device you are using, your direction to refuse cookies may not be implemented.

**Flash Cookies**  
Flash Cookies (also called local stored objects) collect and store information about your preferences and navigation to, from, and on this Site.

**Web Beacons, Clear Pixels, or Pixel Tags**  
Web beacons are transparent image files used to monitor your journey around the Site and can help us understand how you interact with the Site.

**Web server logs**  
Web server logs are a historical record of your activity in connection with your use of the Site. For example, a web server log may record the search term you used that directed you to CosmeticsCop.com. It may also collect information about the browser you use when visiting this Site, and other metadata related to your device.

**Geo-location technologies**  
Geo-location technologies, including your IP address, may help determine your general location to better understand what type of content should be added to Cosmeticscop.com.

#### HOW YOUR INFORMATION MAY BE USED

The Information provided or collected from you is gathered in order to do the following:

  * Make the Site available to you;
  * Provide you with information, products, or services;
  * Fulfill any other purpose for to help respond to the information you provide;
  * Improve the Site’s content and usability; 
  * To provide you with notices about your account if you opt to receive this information.

With your consent, this information may also be used in other ways that would be described at the time you provide the Information to us, and for any other purpose.

#### DISCLOSURE OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

Your Personal Information may be disclosed in the following ways:

To fulfill the purpose for which you provided it (for example, if you provided your email address in order to receive more information about the Site or new content updates, or any other possible services that may be offered, your email address will be used to provide the requested information to you. In order to do this your email address may need to be given to a service provider performing related services on this Site’s behalf, as described below);

To contractors, service providers, and other third-parties CosmeticsCop.com uses to support and improve the content including for such purposes as sending e-mails, providing marketing assistance, analyzing customer data, conducting customer surveys, and providing answers to your questions. 

To the general public only when you include your Personal Information in your posts or comments on the Site, including, product reviews;

To a buyer of or successor to CosmeticsCop.com in the event of a merger, reorganization, dissolution, or other sale or transfer of some or all our business or assets; and to any related companies of CosmeticsCop.com or any such buyer or successor.

Your Personal Information may be disclosed to comply with any court order, law, or legal process, including to respond to any government or regulatory request; and if we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to protect the rights, property, or safety of CosmeticsCop.com or its associates, customers, or others.We may disclose aggregated and anonymous information about our users, and information that does not identify any individual, to third-parties to help us improve the Site.

#### YOUR CHOICES AND OPTING OUT

You have the following choices regarding how your Information is used:

  * To update or correct your Personal Information: You can update your Personal Information by emailing CustServ@CosmeticsCop.com. 
  * To learn what Personal Information CosmeticsCop.com has: You can inquire about what Personal Information CosmeticsCop.com has by emailing CustServ@CosmeticsCop.com.
  * To stop receiving emails from CosmeticsCop.com: You can click on the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of any e-mail you receive from CosmeticsCop.com. 

CosmeticsCop.com reserves the right to email or otherwise contact you with respect to important administrative information, notices or changes relating to your account, reviews and the Site.To remove content posted by you: You can remove content you have posted on a public space on the Site by emailing your request to CustServ@CosmeticsCop.com.

#### YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS

California Civil Code Section §1798.83 permits users of the Site that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of Personal Information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. We do not currently make such disclosures.

#### DATA PROCESSING AND STORAGE

Third party service providers hired by the Site may process or store your personal information outside of the United States (or outside of the country in which you reside, as applicable). In accordance with the laws of those countries, in certain circumstances your personal information may be accessible by foreign law enforcement, regulatory bodies or other authorities.

#### DATA SECURITY

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the Internet is not completely secure. Security measures have been put in place to protect your Personal Information but that protection cannot 100% guarantee the security of your Personal Information. You understand that you are providing your Personal Information at your own risk. Neither CosmeticsCop.com nor Paula Begoun are responsible for failure or circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures that may have in place to protect your Personal Information.

#### CHILDREN UNDER THE AGE OF 13

Personal Information from children under the age of 13 is not knowingly collected. If you are under the age of 13, you should not register or submit Personal Information to this Site. If it it is learned that Personal Information from a child under 13 has been collected or received without verification of parental consent, that information will be immediately deleted. If you believe that any Personal Information from or about a child under 13 has been given to this Site, please contact CustServ@CosmeticsCop.com.

#### CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

This Privacy Policy may be modified or amended from time to time. The date this policy was last revised is identified at the top of this notice and the terms of this policy are effective as of that date.

#### CONTACT INFORMATION

To ask questions or provide comments about this policy and our privacy practices, contact CustServ@CosmeticsCop.com.
